João Santos

Frontend Developer

Personal Info



+351 914 086 424



j-almeidasantos@hotmail.com



j-almeidasantos



isantos42



j-almeidasantos.tech/



Lisbon, PT

[Natural] Languages

English	C2
French	B2
Spanish	B1
Portuguese	C2

[Programming] Languages

[1.1081411111118] Fatileare	
Javascript	Good
React.js	Good
HTML5 & CSS3	Excellent
Node.js (Express)	Intermediate
Python	Good
R	Basic
С	Excellent
C++	Intermediate

Other Tools Git Excellent **Unix Shell** Excellent Shell Scripting Intermediate

Agile (Scrum) & Jira Good

With a background in Medicine and 6+ years of clinical practice, I grew tired of working with poorly-designed and non-intuitive software. The turning point came when I did a datascience project involving geospatial data analysis with Python and R. I liked it so much that I enrolled at 42 to become a developer. Currently, I'm finishing a FullStack course on Udemy, learning Typescript and doing some front-end projects. Passionate and curious by nature, I look forward to join a team and build something great!

Work Experience

Jan 2022 Software Engineer Intern | Critical Techworks

- Jun 2022

- Working on the **frontend** of BMW's cars' infotainment, developing the Human Machine Interface (HMI) of the Navigation panel

- Maintaining the existing codebase (in C++)
- Adding new features and making Unit Tests
- Adding new UI with the QT framework

Oct 2014 - Jul 2021

Student and Medical Doctor | ARSLVT & AP-HP (Paris)

- Medical student and resident "externe" in Paris (Oct 2014 Jul 2016)
- Clerkship in **Uppsala** (Jul 2015)
- GP resident in Lisbon + working shifts in the ER department of the largest hospital in the country (Mar 2018 - Jul 2021)

Some Projects

Portfolio	React.js,
- Website showcasing my main projects (check the link on the sidebar)	JavaScript
Face Detector	React.js, Node.js,
- Fullstack project, with API endpoints and login access	Express.js,
- Use of styled-components , Express.js and a PostgreSQL database	JavaScript
Moves of Pokémons	React.js,
- Website with searchable list, using AJAX requests and a public API	JavaScript
Fast-Food and Schools in Portugal	
- My Master's thesis in Clinical Nutrition, with geospatial data analysis (GIS)	Python,
- Datascience project to find out a potential geographical clustering	R
- Making use of Jupiter notebook and geopandas , numpy , matplolib	
Minishell	С
- A Unix shell, implemented with an Abstract Syntax Tree	C
Dining Philosophers	0.0
- Implementation of a concurrent algorithm, using threads	C, C++
Education .	

Education

- present	42 Lisboa
Sep 2018 - Dec 2021	Master's Degree in Clinical Nutrition Universidade de Lisboa
Sep 2010 - Jul 2016	Doctor of Medicine Universidade de Lisboa & Pierre et Marie Curie Université

Hobbies

Cycling Cooking Reading Learning Traveling Photography